# **Francis Gurr**

★ Sheffield, UK

francisgurr.com

in francis-gurr

Francis-Gurr

## **Summary**

Recent Electronic Engineering (MEng) graduate from Durham University. My main interests lie in software development and machine learning.

I enjoy solving complex problems both independently and as part of a team. I am a fast learner and enjoy widening my skill set by challenging myself with personal I have experience projects. working on large long term projects and can work well in a range of team dynamics. Whilst completing projects I am highly motivated, organised and strive to ensure all my work is of a high standard. These attributes have led me to receive a first in every programming assignment throughout my degree.

### **Skills**

Confident:

Java Python C MatLab LaTeX
CNNs Excel German

Competent:

Javascript C++ Linux Electronics

Experience with:

SQL PHP Graphic Design

### References

#### **Dr Stefano Giani**

Assistant Professor

Durham University

**Stefano.giani@durham.ac.uk** ■ stefano.giani@durham.ac.uk

#### **Colin Reekie**

Head of Development *Q-Free ASA* 

colin.reekie@g-free.com

### **Experience**

Masters Project - 1st Class (80%) Durham University 2019 - 2020

- · Supported by Q-Free ASA.
- Project proposed using road-side video cameras as a non-intrusive alternative to current ITS and infomobility systems.
- Video images were used to determine the speed of vehicles.
- A neural network (YOLOv3) was used for object detection with an accuracy of 98% mAP.
- A Kalman filter was used to track the vehicles.
- Developed software to calibrate the camera using road markings.
- The project proved successful and was able to provide vehicle speeds in real-time from road-side camera footage.

**R&D Intern** *Q-Free ASA, Bristol* 

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- The continuation of a successful third year design project.
- Project managed a group of six students.
- Designed and developed a prototype non-intrusive roadside detection system for counting and classifing vehicles.
- Innovative design using LiDAR and radar.
- Developed custom software to generate 2D side profiles of vehicles using LiDAR data.

**Summer Project** *Durham University* 

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

- Co-author of ancillary software for an academic paper entitled Quartic Graphs that are Bakry-Émery Curvature Sharp.
- Published in Discrete Mathematics 343(3), DOI: 10.1016/j.disc.2019.111767.

### **Education**

**MEng Electronic Engineering - 2:1** Durham University **2015 - 2020** 

• Took a year out following bereavement.

**MChem Chemistry** Durham University

2014 - 2015

• Switched course after year one.

**A Levels** Bournemouth Grammar School

2013 - 2014

• A\* Chemistry, A Maths, A Physics, A German.

### **Achievements**

- Launched first ever Durham Yule Ball with a budget of over £3000, which has been nominated for best student event and commended by the leading student newspaper.
- Founded the Durham Circus Society.
- 2nd place in the Athena Swan Level 1 Essay, entitled *Why are there fewer women in engineering?*.
- Graphic design for Durham Juggling Convention marketing.
- Grade 8 Saxophone, grade 7 Clarinet and grade 3 piano.
- Level 2 Certification in Lean Organisational Management Techniques.